## DEEPAK RAYATHURAI

#### Personal info

Phone: 8220885311

Email:

deepakr6242@protonmail.com

Address: 600117 (IN)

## Skills

Python3.X



**Automation** 



JavascriptAjax Jquery



Problem Management and Change management BMC remedy

AWS ,lambda, buckets,API gateway,Cognitos



HTMI5,CSS



ORM



Rest Apl



**Flask** 



## Professional Summary

To leverage 10 years of technical experience to lead a team or as an individual with exceptional ability and to work collaboratively to develop product, implement solutions, isolate problem and best practices to bring more quality, innovation and business to the organization.

## Employment history

#### Solution Engineer, Fiserv Inc. Chennai

Sep. 2020 - Present

- Full stack development of web applications to augment the DevOps in the organization rather depending on tools.
- Developing customized modules in salt stack for configuration orchestration.
- Finding gaps and leveraging automation across various team of different regions in the organization.
- Analysis, Design, Development, Management, and Implementation of clientserver, web-applications.
- Proposing the apt solutions and implementation for End-to-End Infrastructure automation.
- Enabling and catalyzing the team to drive toward the chaos Engineering.
- · Enforcing the other teams to migrate to cloud.
- Educate and implement on 'Design for Failure' understand how to build highly resilient applications which auto-scale and auto-fail over,
- auto-rebuild etc. address specific components (web vs. database)
- Open Code Initiative Democratize all Code via GIT: cyber specification on which code should be hidden vs. Open (need to know)
- Infrastructure API available to all, with documentation and proper operational support.
- Analyze information to determine, recommend, and plan installation of a new system or modification of an existing system
- Modify existing software to correct errors, to adapt it to new hardware, or to upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Direct software programming and development of documentation.
- Consult with customers or other departments on project status, proposals, or technical issues, such as software system design or maintenance.



- Collaborate with engineers or software developers to select appropriate design solutions or ensure the compatibility of system components.
- Provide technical guidance or support for the development or troubleshooting of systems.

# Senior Associate, COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS. Chennai, TamilNadu

Sep. 2018 - Aug. 2020

- Investigate system component suitability for specified purposes and make recommendations regarding component use.
- Proposing the apt solutions and implementation for End-to-End Infrastructure automation.
- · Driving the team to practice DevOps culture.
- Developing Pipelines in Jenkins for Continuous delivery and Integration for CI/CD.
- Validating the Relevant DevOps tools and prescribing the process for the adoption.
- Analyzing the need for the plugins and developing the required modules in salt stack in python.
- Voluntary Trainer for Devops Academy of the Organization(Cognizant Technologies)
- Delivered 120+ hours of training to Non programmers audience and successfully made them to clear the Internal assessments on saltstack and Configuration Management.
- Helped the Trainees to solve the conventional problems in Configuration management in their project through salt stack.
- Assisted the Academy team to create the technical standard operating procedures for salt stack, which comprise the real time issues in deployment, and solving it through salt stack.
- Delivered webinar session to cognizant on continuous deployments in salt stack.
- Delivered session on how the salt stack can be glued well for continuous testing
- Developing salt formulas in python and Custom libraries for internal use.
- Lead my team in Azure hackathon by building a viable solution on Cognitive Platform indulging image Processing, Compression and predictive models.
- Other Training stacks of my career include Python-Django, Rest Api Development in python, ELK stack, Jenkins, VCS and some prominent services of AWS.
- Won master Performer award twice since Jan2019 for training associates and Creation of Content for Technical Training.
- · Certified in Python for Data Science by IITM.
- Certified as AWS cloud practitioner, Jenkins Engineer, Google Cloud -G suite.
- Working partially as SREs to bring out better solutions and performance and reliability to applications.
- Participated in Microsoft caliber 2.0 hackathon under AI cognitive services and made to final round.

## Senior Software Engineer, Wipro Technologies. Chennai, Tamilnadu Jul. 2011 – Aug. 2018

- Technical specialist for bank's digital applications such as Mobile banking, Internet Banking and other branch applications, encored on ZK framework for 3 years, which includes 2 Years of offshore and 4 years of onsite experience at South Africa Standard Bank.
- Writing and assisting team to write reusable, testable and efficient programs.
- Provided training on the salt stack, Jenkins and Python to WIPRO Engineers through volunteer mentoring program.
- Spent 300+ manhours since 2017 in providing training on python and Devops tools.
- Designing, developing and deploying the application and providing Solutions to bring innovative and worthwhile product to End Users.
- Writing watchers and Triggers in ELK stack to get the thresholds and Bottlenecks of the application
- Using APM in ELK stack to bring the developed Django Applications to achieve better scalability and take care proactive measures for security violations and organization defined security policies.
- Tunneled ELK stack to get the analysis on how automation of Quality engineering is practiced which enable the bank to get the statistics on the Digital transformation
- Enabled the Server logs to get stashed and monitoring using the logs and alerting the infrastructure team to take proactive measures.
- Conversion of Business excel data to Metrics and visualizations in Kibana.
- Adopting and ensuring the standards for the development platform and for the process in the project.
- Validation of UI to provide best UX to end Users.
- Code debugging and data fixes activities.
- Integrating multiple data sources and databases into one system
- · Unit test and debugging skills
- Proficient understanding of Source version control systems like GIT, Bit Bucket, JIRA and Confluence.
- Generating MIS reports and documentation.
- Analyzing user inconvenience and bugs in the application.
- Conducting technical analysis with team to increase the performance of the applications.
- Fix advice to the other partner system development team and technical recommendations in Design and new application features.
- · Identifying and fixing performance issues.
- Developing Programs and application as value add to automate the activities wherever and whenever possible using Python.
- Project Deployments, Post Deployments Support and Go Live Support.
- Root Cause Analysis for all critical, high and recurring Incidents in Bank Production Environment.
- Problem Management.
- Monitoring SLAs and adopting best practices to pursue it always.
- Escalating the Unresolved Issues at the right time and finding permanent resolutions to ensure the customer satisfaction all the time.
- To provide the analysis to Bank Authorized Users, including actions required to rectify the issue.
- Steps, Plans and Implementations to prevent the incident from re-occurring.
- Work closely with appropriate personnel to provide Progress reporting and effective Incident and Problem resolution in Production.

- . Monitoring servers and taking proactive measures to ensure availability.
- Debugging Web Based Applications written in JAVA.
- Leading the team in competitive programs and went to second round of standard Bank Johannesburg Hackathon 2017.
- Learning new technologies and mentoring the team on the same and training technically and qualitatively.
- Developing relevant applications as plugin to enhance customer experience.
- Led Digital Lab in the organization which concentrates on Artificial Intelligence, Machine learning and Robotics Process Automation.
- Hands on in Amazon web services, Microsoft Azure solutions, and Selenium Web driver.
- Developed a mobile app using Power apps for standard bank users to provide their surveys on digital applications
- Led my team in competitive program and solved the problem of converting the customer feedback and sentiments into powerful business insights.

## **Education**

**KUMARAGURU COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY, Coimbatore, Tamilnadu**Bachelor Of Engineering, Electrical and Electroncis Engineering, Apr. 2011